A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Office of Communications, Office Files of Mary Loftus FA1428
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Office of Communications, Office Files of Mary Loftus
1975-2005
1995-1999
Rockefeller Archive Center
Loftus, Mary
Ford Foundation
FA1428
1.14 Cubic Feet 3 document containers
Scope and Contents
Mary Loftus served as the Manager of Information Dissemination and Administration in the Office of Communications at the Ford Foundation. This collection is composed of her office files, including correspondence, annual report draft files, and files related to the creation of the Ford Foundation's early website. The bulk of the material in the collection spans from 1995-1999.
Arrangement
Arranged as received from the Ford Foundation in 2017
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This material was transferred to RAC in 2017 by the Ford Foundation and ingested by RAC as Accession 2017:087.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Biographical / Historical
The Ford Foundation was chartered by Henry and Edsel Ford in 1936 "to receive and administer funds for scientific, educational and charitable purposes, all for the public welfare", and initially served the Ford family's charitable interests in the Detroit area. Following the deaths of Edsel Ford (1943) and Henry Ford (1947), the Foundation was propelled to the forefront of philanthropy as the largest American foundation in terms of both endowment and yearly expenditures, and with an international scope to its major program areas.
During the Foundation's first twenty years its major programs were in international economic development, primary and higher education, educational and public broadcasting, behavioral sciences, civil liberties, urban development, fine arts and the humanities. The Ford Foundation also partnered with the Rockefeller Foundation in supporting agricultural development in South America, Africa, and Southeast Asia. Since the 1970s, the Foundation has also pioneered programs in women's rights, energy policy, micro-financing in under-developed countries, establishing human rights groups, and improving international HIV/AIDS education.
Mary Loftus served as the Manager of Information Dissemination and Administration in the Office of Communications at the Ford Foundation.
Communications; Ford Foundation
- Ford Foundation Letter - Index, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Contract with University Microfilms International (re Letter and Copyright for Letter), 1975 April-2000 November (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Internet/Web Site Background, 1995 December-1997 October (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Ford Foundation Website Log Information: Publication Requests, 1997 February-2004 February (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Ford Foundation Web Site Flap File, 1997-1999 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Web Site Permissions File, 1996 October-1998 August (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Ford Foundation Website - Bills, 1998 June-2000 January (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Website Contracts, Etc., 1998 April-December (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Equipment File - Purchase Orders, 1995-1999 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Mary Loftus Correspondence, 1999 June-September (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Mary Loftus Correspondence, 1999 October-December (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Mary Loftus Chron File, 1999 January-March (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Mary Loftus Chron File, 1998 October-December (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Mary Loftus Chron File, 1998 July-September (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Mary Loftus Chron File, 1999 April-June (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Office of Communications Purchase Order Logs, 1998 September-1999 October (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Annual Report 1999, 1998 September-2000 May (Box 2, Folder 17)
  Scope and Contents
  Correspondence, quotes from printers, printing specifications, general mailing list
- Job #97-13A 1997 Annual Report - General, 1997 December-1998 November (Box 2, Folder 18-20)
- Job #97-13C 1997 Annual Report - Officers/Trustees/Directors, 1997 March-1998 June (Box 2, Folder 21-22)
- Job #97-12E 1997 Annual Report - Representatives, 1998 March-July (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Job #97-13H 1997 Annual Report - Poll File, 1998 February-June (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Ford Foundation in Listings and Directories, 1989-2005 (Box 3, Folder 25-28)